NEHREET **Kaur**

1900 Simond Avenue # 4061, Austin, TX - 78723 🏗

+1-908-381-4165

kaur.nehreet@gmail.com

LinkedIn in

GitHub



To obtain an entry-level full-time position as a Full-Stack Web Developer.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am an experienced professional with **7+ years** of experience in the healthcare industry in the United Kingdom (UK). I hold a Bachelor's degree in **Internet Sciences** and am currently pursuing the Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp at University of Texas, Austin in **Web-Development**. Effective at combining creativity, problem solving and working as a team to develop user-friendly applications.

EDUCATION

Full-stack Coding Bootcamp | University of Texas, Austin, USA 2020 – 2021

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Flexbox, Bootstrap, API, JSON, AJAX, Node.js, SQL

Bachelor of Internet Sciences | Kurukshetra University, India 2000 – 2003

Programming Languages: C++, Java

CODING PROJECTS

- Developed an interactive website called "Cocktails on the Run" which allows users to search a cocktail by name and retrieve the instructions and ingredients for making the specified cocktail. In addition, the user is provided with the nearest bars/restaurants serving the drink.
 - o Languages: HTML, CSS, Flexbox, JavaScript
- Developed a website of "Day Planner" in which the user can enter an event in time-blocks. These time-blocks are color-coded based on the past, present and future events.

- Languages: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript
- Developed a webpage for "Random Password Generator" in which the user enters the prompts and confirms. Thereafter, the user is provided with a unique password.
 - o Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Developed a prompt in which the user is prompted with questions about the Manager, Employee and Intern on a command terminal. Thereafter, an HTML file is generated.
 - o Languages: HTML, CSS, Node.js, Inquirer
- Developed a web project "Fun with Filters" wherein the user can upload an image file on the web page and apply various color/contrast filters onto the image.
 - o Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Developed a complete full-stack application about "Petfinder/Adoption". In this application, user can login with Google and explore the application and post comments. If the user is not logged in, they cannot explore the application. When a user posts a comment, it shows in the database the posted comments.
 - o Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, BULMA, Pure-CSS, Node.js, SQL, Google-Oauth2.



CERTIFICATIONS

JS, CSS and HTML for Web | Johns Hopkins University, USA 2020

Programming with JS, HTML and CSS | Duke University, USA 2020

Level-3 Promote good practices in Social Care | City and Guilds, UK 2012

Level-2 NVQ in Health and Social Care | City and Guilds, UK 2008

First Aid | Birmingham City Council, UK 2010 – 2013



WORK EXPERIENCE

Care Assistant | Birmingham City Council, UK 04/2014 – 12/2014

Direct Care Provider | Birmingham City Council, UK 09/2009 – 02/2013

Care Assistant | Birmingham City Council, UK

- 06/2006 08/2009
- Worked for the care of elderly people with care professionals (General Practitioner, Registered Nurses, Psychiatrists, Nutritionists, Social Workers).
- Developed excellent communication skills and showed exemplary teamwork while demonstrating strong ethics and integrity.
- Mentored new recruits and guided them to gain experience as a care provider.



- Strong Programming Fundamentals
- Excellent Verbal and Written Communication Skills

- Focused and Driven
- High Integrity and Strong Ethics
- Team Player and Keen Learner